

Vincent Duchauffour
Data Scientist

Paris, France

2 06.09.78.66.27

☑ vincent.duchauffour@proton.me

Linkedin

% Github

Profile

Former social science student.

My interest in computer science and mathematics led me to reorient my professional project towards data science.

My first experience as a data analyst allowed me to focus on business oriented data analysis and analytics engineering.

My current experience allowed me to confirm this career path by contributing to

firm this career path by contributing to data science projects in production-ready context.

Skills

- Python
- Scikit-Learn, PyTorch
- Linux, Git, Docker
- GCP, DVC, W&B
- SQL, Elasticsearch, MongoDB

Languages

- French (Native)
- English (B2)

Experience

Since Oct. 2022 Machine Learning Engineer - Kinetix

- Rewrite large part of the codebase with strong OOP principes (SOLID principes / Anti-code smells policy)
- Reduce by 50% the inference time on the main ML pipeline (PyTorch, profilers)

Sep. 2021 - Sep. 2022 Data Scientist - Yanport

- Design, build and deploy an improvement on existing NLP system with ordinal classification with focus on explainability (NLTK, Spacy, PyTorch, HuggingFace)
- Design, build and deploy new features on the home value estimate engine (CatBoost)
- Maintain and deploy data pipelines and internal scipting
- \bullet EDA and ad hoc analyses for external client

Sep. 2019 - Sep. 2021 Data analyst - Qare

- Design, build and deploy a monitoring tool for data and ETLs quality
- Analytics engineering (DBT)
- Contributing to ETLs and RETLs (MongoDB, AWS Redshift, Salesforce)
- EDA and ad hoc analyses, interact with concerned corporate departments and make public presentation of results
- Build Tableau dashboards

Education

2021 - 2022

Msc Data Science (IASD) - Paris Dauphine - Apprenticeship

Master thesis: Improving an existing NLP system with ordinality, a deep
dive into explainability

2019 - 2021

Msc Digital Humanities - CNAM - Apprenticeship

Master thesis: Data analysis for efficient telemedecine customer service

• Programming, Statistics, ML concepts, Linear models, Clustering

Math evening classes - CNAM

 Analysis, Linear algebra, Graph theory, Linear optimisation, Probabilities, Statistics

2012-2017

Bachelor & Master Philosophy - Paris Nanterre